Asher Clawson

Cedar Hills, Utah 84062 | (801) 960-5641 | aacpogona@me.com https://github.com/KingPogona |

Summary

Full stack web developer with four years of experience working in IT, support, QA, regression testing development, and maintenance of company Hardware and software. Experience with agile methodologies and as assistant DBA and software developer. Love for learning new skills, problem solving and incorporating new tools, methods, and technologies. Successfully developed, researched, and implemented solutions to many difficult and diverse problems to accelerate team productivity and meet or exceed project goals.

Technical Skills

HTML, CSS, Javascript, NodeJS, SQL, Mongo, Express GraphQL and React. Excel Macros using VBA, Python, C++, Development with microcontrollers and SBCs.

Education

Full Stack Web Development Certificate - University Of Utah | 2021

Experience

Web Developer 2020-Current

Young Living; Provo, UT

•

Software Engineer

2018-2020

ProfitStance; Provo, UT

Diagnosed, troubleshot, and resolved employee hardware, software, or other network and system problems. Assisted with the configuration and maintenance company networking, teleconferencing and related hardware and software. Configured, monitored, and administered company software deployments. Conducted software compatibility tests with programs, hardware, operating systems, or network environments.

- Developed an excel macro that accelerated crypto account statement format conversions by 100%. Conversion time went from hours or even days by hand to milliseconds.
- Detected issues to ensure quality assurance by conducting automated testing, developing a scheduled daily regression testing suite that would automatically report if part of the site was live and functioning properly, had browser or OS incompatibilities, and issues caused by crypto exchange API updates.
- Promoted efficiency by writing and maintaining computer programs, or Excel VBA macros, to assist employees with processing or converting data.

Assistant Database Administrator | Information Technology

2015-2017

WESHARE; Woods Cross, UT

Maintained and enhanced a geo-location database with over 151,000 cities, towns, and other municipalities from more than 200 countries. Validation of user transactions and accounts for international credit card transactions. Administered system and user IT support.